disabilitynewsservice.com 2019-11-28

# Privacy Policy – Disability News Service

You are here: [Home](https://www.disabilitynewsservice.com/) / Privacy Policy

This is the privacy policy for: [www.disabilitynewsservice.com](https://www.disabilitynewsservice.com/)

It explains how Disability News Service collects, uses and stores your personal data as part of our work to provide disability-related news stories to our readers.

DNS will do its best to protect your personal data, respect your privacy and use that information only for the purposes for which it was collected, and for as long as it is needed.

## What personal data DNS collects and why it is collected

Personal data is information about visitors to the website that can identify them, such as names, email addresses, phone numbers and information about your mobile phone, computer or tablet, such as its IP address.

The information is collected to help DNS provide its news stories, offer advertising opportunities, and analyse how visitors use the site.

When you use the site, we may use cookies or similar technology to collect other data, such as:

  * Your IP address, which can tell us the city or country where you are based
  * The content you have visited on the site, including how you were referred to DNS via another website
  * Details about your mobile phone, tablet or laptop.

When you contact DNS by telephone, email or via social media, for example for editorial purposes, we may collect your personal data in order to contact you again in the future. If you ask us to delete this information we will do so, if we have no lawful grounds for retaining that information.

Payments to DNS, for example by those making voluntary payments to support its work, are usually made via PayPal. We need to keep that information for tax reasons. [PayPal’s privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) explains in more depth how PayPal handles data.

We use social media plug-ins from organisations such as Twitter and Facebook. If you use their services to visit DNS they may use your personal data about your visit to DNS. They have their own privacy policies about how they use your personal data:

We also use text-to-speech services provided by ReadSpeaker. [Click here](https://www.readspeaker.com/privacy-policy/) for their privacy policy.

And we use Google Analytics to keep track of how many people visit the DNS website:

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on DNS may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Who DNS shares your data with

DNS does not share your personal information with other organisations for marketing purposes.

If you click on an advert to visit the website of that advertiser, that organisation is likely to have its own privacy policy relating to its use of your data. Please view that policy if you have any concerns.

The DNS site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by Sucuri’s SiteCheck. We do not send personal information to Sucuri; however, Sucuri could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during their scan.

For more details, please see [Sucuri’s privacy policy](https://sucuri.net/privacy).

This site is part of a network of sites that protect against distributed brute force attacks. To enable this protection, the IP address of visitors attempting to log into the site is shared with a service provided by ithemes.com. For privacy policy details, please see the [iThemes Privacy Policy](https://ithemes.com/privacy-policy).

## Contact details

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

The data controller for [www.disabilitynewssservice.com](http://www.disabilitynewssservice.com/) is John Pring, editor of Disability News Service.

For any privacy concerns or questions or to access the personal information we hold about you, contact him via email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#e882878086a88c819b898a8184819c91868d9f9b9b8d9a9e818b8dc68b8785) or by phone, on: 020 8241 7072 or 07776 206595. He will aim to respond to you within one working day, except for those weeks when he is on leave.
